お前が死ぬ…
あのＤメールを
消せば―
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）
ベータ世界線に戻れば
If we return to the beta world line...
If we undo that first D-mail...
～
Being
Meltdown
You will die.
So there you are.
（岡部）ここだったか…
If you keep lying there, you'll get heatstroke.
こんな所で寝ていると
熱中症になるぞ
You sleep on the roof of the lab all the time, anyway, don't you?
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）
あんただって ラボの屋上で
寝っ転がってたでしょ？
Besides, it's cloudy now.
それに今は曇ってる
まゆりには会えたの？
Did you see Mayuri?
Hashida said he couldn't find her at Comima.
橋田(はしだ)が コミマでは
会えなかったみたいって
Yeah.
（岡部）ああ…
I met up with her after that.
その後 会えた
そう
I see.
Hey, Okabe.
（紅莉栖）ねえ… 岡部
What?
（岡部）なんだ？
ん？
分かった
All right.
ん…
Hey.
おい
雨だぞ
It's raining.
あっ
（岡部･紅莉栖）うわあっ
What the hell is this?
（紅莉栖）なんぞ これ！
（２人の荒い息遣い）
（紅莉栖）
もう少し早く忠告してよ
Why didn't you warn me earlier?
おかげで下着まで
びしょぬれじゃない もう…
I'm soaked down to my underwear.
I told you so.
（岡部）ちゃんと声はかけた
It's your fault, Christina, for not listen—
聞いていなかったのは
クリスティーナの…
おっ…
（紅莉栖）へっ？
なっ！ この変態！
Y-You pervert!
別に見ようと思って
見たわけではないぞ
I wasn't exactly trying to look.
It's your fault for wearing such thin clothes.
貴様が そんな透けやすい服を
着ているのが…
I almost forgot you were such a pervert.
あんたが変態だってこと
忘れてたわ
Who would want to see your featureless figure in the nude?
お前の貧相なヌードなど
見るに値するとでも…
One more word, and I'll turn your neocortex into a flower pot!
それ以上言ったら―
あんたの大脳新皮質を
ポン酢漬けにしてやるから！
What kind of threat is that?
（岡部）どういう脅しだ
（紅莉栖）近づかないで！
Stay away from me!
あっ…
…って何それ？
What's that?
（岡部）ん？ あっ…
I got scratched somewhere while I was looking for you.
お前を捜しているとき
どこかに ひっかけたか…
フンッ ドジっ子
Klutz!
I'm what you'd call a "mad scientist."
俺の属性は
マッドサイエンティストで…
Yeah, yeah.
はいはい
まったく世話が焼けるわね
You're so much trouble.
Hand that over.
貸して
I have a sewing kit on me.
ちょうどソーイングセットが
あるから縫ってあげる
I'll fix it up.
A sewing kit?
ソーイングセット？
I consider myself more family oriented than most people.
これでも相対的に見れば
家庭的なほうなのよ
Take it off.
ほら 脱いで
あ… 先に言っておくけど―
Just to be clear,
この暗さだから
出来については期待しないこと
it's dark, so don't expect too much.
You can look forward to finding out what color thread I used after we leave.
あと 糸が何色になるか
出てからのお楽しみね
Black, red, pink...
黒 赤 ピンク
確率は３分の１
You have a 33% chance for each one.
I'll just pray it isn't pink.
（岡部）
ピンクが出ないよう祈ろう
（紅莉栖）ちょ… 来ないでよ
Stay back.
Don't worry.
（岡部）安心しろ
お前の貧相なヌードに興味…
I'm not interested in that stick figure—
I told you... A flower pot!
ポン酢漬けにするって
言ってんだろ
ハア… まったく…
Geez...
Where could you have gone to rip your clothes like this?
どこをぶらついたら
こんな所 破けるのよ
（岡部）今日はラボに行って―
Today, I went to the lab,
to the laundromat,
ランドリー 散歩
and on a walk.
それから―
Then, I went to your hotel.
お前が泊まっているホテル
（紅莉栖）
ホテル？ 行ったの？
The hotel? You stopped by?
お前のせいだぞ
It's your fault.
You wouldn't answer my messages.
メールの返信は よこさない
You weren't picking up your phone.
電話にも出ない
Were you worried about me?
まさか 心配してくれて…
As head of the lab, it's my job to keep track of my assistant.
（岡部）
助手の管理はラボのあるじである
俺の仕事だからな
Is it done yet?
まだ出来ないのか？
Almost.
（紅莉栖）
ちょっと待って
（紅莉栖）ほれっ！
（岡部）うわっ
Here!
That's cold. Hey!
（岡部）冷たっ！ お前
（紅莉栖）早く着なさい
Just put it on.
マッドサイエンティストの
貧相なヌードなど―
I'm not interested in the stick figure of a nude mad scientist.
興味ないのだからな
フーッハッハッハッ
（岡部）ああっ…
It was probably around here, right?
（紅莉栖）多分…
この近くよね
The place I was stabbed...
私が―
刺された場所
なっ…
How did you know?
（岡部）どうして… それを？
The pain and despair were too real for a dream.
（紅莉栖）やっぱり…
夢にしては痛さや絶望感が
あまりにリアルだったから
Kurisu, you can't mean...
（岡部）紅莉栖…
まさか お前…
うん
私の中にもね―
I have some hazy memories.
ぼんやりと記憶があるの
They're weak, almost nonexistent memories,
淡い―
まるで
幻みたいな記憶
and not just of being stabbed.
刺されたときのこと
だけじゃない
I also remember you a little bit.
岡部のことも
ぼんやりと覚えてる
How desperate you were to save Mayuri.
まゆりを助けようと
必死になって―
How you kept pressing forward,
一人で傷つきながらも
前に進もうとしているの
in pain and all alone.
You haven't made it back to your original world,
決して元の世界には
戻せないのに
yet you kept going,
それでも
必死にあらがって―
kept calling her name,
まゆりの名前を必死で叫んで―
kept crying...
涙を流して―
and kept trying to save her.
ひたむきに助けようとしている
岡部がいるの
Every time I see that face,
その顔を見るたびに
私は思うの…
I think about how important she is to you...
岡部にとって―
どれだけ まゆりが
掛けがえのない存在か…
and whether it's possible for someone
to truly care for another person that much.
誰かが誰かを―
ここまで
大切に思えるのかって…
That's why I wanted to work with you.
だから私は
岡部に協力したい
岡部の手助けをしたいと思った
That's why I wanted to help you.
Okabe, save Mayuri.
ねえ 岡部
まゆりを助けて
You must save her.
岡部は―
まゆりを助けるべきなのよ
If we go to the beta world line,
お前はどうなる
ベータ世界線に行ったら
死ぬんだぞ
you'll die!
But it's the only way.
でも
そうするしかないの
You know that better than anyone, right?
あんたが一番
よく分かってるでしょ？
選択肢は１つしかない
There's only one option.
Stop!
（岡部）お前を―
You're telling me to abandon you?
見捨てろって言うのか？
Is there any other way?
（紅莉栖）ほかに方法がある？
I've been thinking about it since yesterday.
昨日から何度も考えた
"Isn't there some other way?"
今までみたいに何か打つ手が―
"Isn't there something else we can do?"
何か方法が
あるんじゃないかって
But this time, I can't come up with anything...
でも 無理…
今度ばかりは
どうしようもない
except going to the beta world line.
ベータ世界線に行くしか
方法はないの
Okabe!
岡部！
I refuse to accept this.
こんなの 俺は認めない
I won't give up!
あきらめない！
I can't...
（岡部）できるわけないだろ
I can't abandon Kurisu.
紅莉栖を見捨てるなんて
あいつを見殺しにして
生きていくなんて
I can't let her die while I keep on living.
What would be the point?
そんなことに何の意味がある
俺は…
I...
ハッ
ハアッ ハアッ
You can run away.
（紅莉栖）逃げたって―
You can run away, but that'll just make it worse!
逃げたって
苦しくなるだけよ！
Shut up!
（岡部）うるさい！
No matter how many times you time leap,
何度タイムリープしたって
１％の壁は越えられない！
you can't get past the 1% barrier!
We won't know until we try!
（岡部）
やってみなきゃ分からないだろ！
You'll just see Mayuri die again!
まゆりが死ぬところを
見るだけなのよ？
Many times again.
何回も…
It'll destroy you.
そんなの
岡部が壊れちゃう
It won't.
（岡部）壊れなど… しない
How many times do you think I've watched her die?
俺が何回 まゆりの死を
見てきたと思ってる？
I've seen it over...
何回も見てきた…
and over and over and over
何回も 何回も 何回も
何回も 何回も…
and over and over.
もう そんなもので
心が壊れたりしない
It won't destroy me, no matter how many times I see it!
何度繰り返そうが同じ…
Do you hear what you're saying?
（紅莉栖）自分が
何言ってるか分かってる？
Mayuri's going to suffer and die.
まゆりが
苦しんで死んでいくのよ
“そんなもの”のわけ
ないじゃない
How can you say it doesn't matter?
If that doesn't affect you,
それで岡部の心が
動かないんだとしたら―
then your heart's already broken.
もう 岡部の心は壊れている…
Just stop...
もうやめて
本当に壊れちゃうよ…
or you'll really break.
（岡部）分かってる
I know.
I noticed it long ago.
気づいてた
No matter how many times Mayuri died, I stopped being surprised.
まゆりが何度も死んでいるのに
俺は驚かなくなっていた
いつの間にか―
I became desensitized without even knowing it.
心がマヒしていた
Sometimes, I even waited before time leaping, just to see when she'd die.
まゆりが死ぬ時刻を
確かめようと―
タイムリープせずに
待っていたことすらあった
At some point,
まゆりが死ぬのに―
俺の心は いつからか
動かなくなって…
it just stopped affecting me.
冷静に やり直せばいいって―
Somewhere inside, I was calmly telling myself that I could do it over.
どこかで そう思ってて…
Save Mayuri.
まゆりを 助けて
If you don't, it'll truly destroy you.
そうしないと
本当に岡部が壊れてしまう
まゆりを
見殺しになんかしたら―
If you let her die, you'll regret it for sure!
絶対に後悔する
まゆりを
助けようっていう思いだけで―
You and I have come this far with our only wish being to save her!
岡部と私は ここまで来た
ここでやめたら
一生 後悔し続ける
If we stop, we'll only regret it.
But if we save her,
（岡部）
でも まゆりを助けたら お前は
you'll—
I'll just go back!
戻るだけよ！
Ｄメールが送られなかった
最初の世界線に
To the first world line, before the D-mail was sent!
That's what's best for me,
それが 私のためであり
岡部のためでもある
and it's what's best for you too!
How many times have we fought over these past 20 days?
（岡部）
この20日間 何度も衝突した
We made fun of each other.
互いに憎まれ口をたたきあった
We talked about our problems.
相談し合ったりもした
追い詰められた俺が
助けを求めたのは紅莉栖だった
When my back was against the wall, I turned to Kurisu.
Kurisu was the one who listened to me,
俺の話を黙って聞き―
信じてくれたのは紅莉栖だった
who believed in me.
At 18, she was already a genius with a published academic paper.
18歳で学術誌に論文が載った
天才少女は―
常に冷静で強がりで―
Always calm, always strong-willed,
always so proud and nosy,
プライドが高くて
おせっかいで―
but also always so kind and honest.
根は真面目すぎるほど真面目で―
Her theories continually amazed me,
俺は いつだって―
彼女の語る理論にシビれて―
and I remembered everything she said
彼女の言葉を胸に刻み込んで―
and watched everything she did.
彼女の動きを目で追っていた
She wasn't just another lab member.
単なる仲間じゃない
To me, Makise Kurisu was...
俺にとって牧瀬紅莉栖は…
I can't save you.
（岡部）俺は―
お前を助けられない
I'm sorry.
すまない…
ありがとう
Thank you
私のために―
for going through so much for me.
そこまで苦しんでくれて
Why was it you?
なんで お前なんだって
どうして お前なんだって
Why you?!
Hey, what does it mean to change world lines?
（紅莉栖）ねえ
世界線が変わるって
どういうことなんだろう？
Maybe the second you go to the beta world line,
もしかしたら 岡部が
ベータ世界線に行った瞬間―
この世界から岡部という存在が
消えるだけかもしれない
you'll just disappear from this world.
Or maybe you trade places with another Okabe.
別の岡部という存在に
変わるのかもしれない
That doesn't matter.
（岡部）そんなの意味がない
（紅莉栖）そんなことない
That's not true.
I'm not dead.
私は死んでない
Even if I'm dead in the beta world line,
ベータ世界線の私が
死んでいたとしても
there's no guarantee that I'm going to die here!
今ここにいる私が死ぬ保証は
どこにもない
There could be another me
無数の世界線に
別の私がいるかもしれない
amidst all the other infinite world lines,
and our minds are connected and comprise "me."
その意志が つながって―
自分という存在が
あるのかもしれない
Don't you think that'd be wonderful?
それって―
ステキだと思わない？
あらゆる時 あらゆる場所に
自分がいる
You'd be everywhere in every timeline, all at once.
A great love for someone,
誰かを愛する強い気持ちが
何かを信じる強い感情が―
a great belief in something,
a great desire to pass on something...
何かを伝えたいという
強い思いが―
If all those things surpass time itself and create "you,"
時を超え つながって―
今の自分があるのだとしたら―
wouldn't that be wonderful?
それは すばらしいこと
だから 見殺しにするなんて
思わないで
So don't think of it as abandoning me.
Even if the world line changes,
世界線が変わっても
たった一人―
岡部が忘れなければ
私は そこにいる
as long as you don't forget me, I'll be there.
So...
だから…
（岡部）お前のことは
絶対に忘れない
I'll never forget you.
I won't forget the person I care for most.
誰よりも大切な人のことを
忘れたりしない
Does that mean...
それって…
事実だ
It's the truth.
H-How? This is so sudden.
そんなこと… なんで急に
I'm in love with you.
俺は お前が好きだ
What about you?
お前は どうなんだ？
…っと 言いますと？
What do you mean?
I want to hear your response.
聞いておきたいんだ
お前は俺のことを
どう思ってる？
How do you feel about me?
（紅莉栖）知りたいのか？
You want to know?
（岡部）ああ
Yeah.
（紅莉栖）顔は…
Your face... Close your eyes.
（岡部）えっ？
（紅莉栖）目を閉じろ
（岡部）どうして
（紅莉栖）いいから 閉じなさいよ
Why?
Just do it!
（紅莉栖）べ… 別に
したくてしたわけじゃないから
I-I didn't want to do that, okay?
But experiences such as your first kiss
ただ ファーストキスのような
強烈な行為とともに―
are stored in the hippocampus with your strong memories, which are harder to forget.
海馬に記憶されたエピソードは
忘却されにくいのよ
Thus—
（紅莉栖）だから…
（岡部）残念だったな
Sorry.
That wasn't my first kiss.
俺は これが
ファーストキスではない
You insolent virgin!
生意気な！ 童貞のくせに
うるさい！ 処女
Silence, little girl.
My first kiss wasn't at all romantic.
もっとも
ファーストキスは―
ロマンチックなものでは
なかったがな
Anyway...
とにかく…
今のは印象としては弱い
that last one only left a weak impression.
もう一度だ
How about one more?
（紅莉栖）えっ？ あっ…
I don't want to forget, not ever,
（岡部）
絶対に忘れたくないから
念には念を入れる
so I'll take extra care.
いいな？
Well, I guess that's okay.
（紅莉栖）
それなら しょうがないな…
Just a kiss, right?
キス… だけだぞ
Time is passing so quickly.
（紅莉栖）時間が
あっという間に流れていく
今だけは―
Right now, I feel like complaining to Einstein.
アインシュタインに
文句を言いたい気分
ねえ 岡部
You know, Okabe,
whether time passes slowly or quickly
時間は人の意識によって―
depends on your perception.
長くなったり
短くなったりする
相対性理論って
とてもロマンチックで―
The theory of relativity is so romantic...
and so sad.
とても切ないものだね
Goodbye then.
（紅莉栖）それじゃあ
（岡部）まゆりとダルは
本当にいいのか？
Are you sure about not saying it to Mayuri and Daru?
（紅莉栖）みんなに見送られると
つらくなるから
Everyone seeing me off would just make it worse.
If it's only you,
岡部だけなら
何のためらいもなく日本をたてる
I can leave Japan without any hesitation.
That was a joke.
フッ　ジョークよ
（岡部）手土産だ 受け取れ
Here's a present.
Take it.
（紅莉栖）ああ…
I don't want this.
いらねえ…
I upgraded it to version 2.67.
バージョン2,67に
アップデートしてある
What a pain.
ややこしいわね
But I'll take it anyway.
でも まあ 受け取っておく
じゃあ
Bye.
Kurisu!
（岡部）紅莉栖
（紅莉栖）そうだ！
Right!
This is for you!
お返し
えいっ
（岡部）あ…
Where were you aiming?
どこに投げている
Go get it!
（紅莉栖）ちゃんと受け取れ
Geez...
…ったく
（紅莉栖）岡部
Okabe...
I'm sure that, whatever happens, you're going to suffer.
これから きっと―
岡部はつらい思いをする
Only you will remember me
私のことを
誰も覚えていない世界で―
ただ一人 私を覚えているなんて
in a world where no one else does.
More than anyone else, you care for your friends,
仲間を何より
大事にする岡部には―
so it'll be painful for you.
つらいことだと思う
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
But somehow, I'm glad you'll carry that pain.
でも 私には
そのつらさが いとおしい
For those times when you're sitting around the lab...
ラボにいる何気ない時間―
When you drink a can of juice...
ジュースを口にしたとき―
When you walk around town...
街を歩くその一瞬―
And someday, when you kiss someone...
いつか誰かとキスしたとき―
いつもじゃなくてもいい―
It doesn't have to be every time.
100回に１回でもいい―
It can be one time out of a hundred,
私を思い出してほしい
but I'd like you to remember me
そこに私はいるから
because I'll be there.
I'll be there, beyond the 1% barrier!
１％の壁の向こうに―
私は必ずいるから
岡部
Okabe...
Okabe.
岡部…
Okabe!
Oh, shit!
（橋田 至(いたる)）あった！
オカリン 見つけた
Okarin, I found it.
This is it.
マジで あったぞ
これっしょ？
Looks like someone
stabbed Makise Kurisu.
This is totally it!
If we delete this...
これを消せば…
Mission complete.
ミッション コンプリート？
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）
オカリン 大丈夫？
Okarin,
are you okay?
I'm fine...
大丈夫だ
We now begin the final phase of Operation Verdandi!
これより
オペレーションベルダンディ―
最終フェイズを開始する！
Our victory is nigh!
勝利の時は来た！
We've overcome all conspiracies,
あらゆる陰謀に屈せず
己の… 己の信念を貫き―
upholding our ideals to the very end.
And finally, we've fought through the battle of Ragnarok!
我々は ついに
ラグナロックを戦い抜いたのだ！
I thank those who've worked so hard for me
この勝利のために―
我が手足となって戦ってくれた
仲間たちに感謝を！
to ensure this victory!
犠牲となった すべての思いに
感謝を！
I am grateful to all those I've had to sacrifice.
訪れるのは―
What comes now is the world I wished for!
俺が
望んだ世界であり―
すべては―
This is all the choice of Steins Gate!
シュタインズ･ゲートの選択である
The world...
世界は―
will be rebuilt!
再構築される！
（岡部）紅莉栖
Kurisu...
I'm sorry.
すまない…
（紅莉栖）岡部！
Okabe!
ハアッ ハアッ ハアッ
Okabe...
岡部 私も…
I'm also...
紅莉栖！
Kurisu!
I'm also in...
私も 岡部のことが
ハッ
まゆり
Mayuri,
（まゆり）ん？
who is Lab Member 004?
ラボメンナンバー００４は誰だ？
004?
（まゆり）００４？ んん…
There isn't a 004.
００４の人は いないよ？
フフフッ
今！
Now the battle of Ragnarok has ended!
ここにラグナロックの
勝敗は決した！
I, the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma, have conquered time itself,
この俺―
狂気のマッドサイエンティスト
である鳳凰院凶真(ほうおういんきょうま)は―
foiling the Organization and SERN's schemes,
機関およびＳＥＲＮ(セルン)の
あらゆる攻撃に対し―
and brought about complete victory!
時空を操ることで―
完全に勝利したのだ！
The world's power structure has been reset,
世界の支配構造はリセットされ―
and a future of chaos awaits!
混沌(こんとん)の未来が待つであろう
This is the choice of Steins Gate!
これこそが
シュタインズ･ゲートの選択
オカリン
Okarin, it's all right.
もういいんだよ
What are you saying?
何を… 俺は今
華麗なる勝利宣言を…
I just issued a declaration of victory.
You don't have to talk like that anymore.
もう その口調 続けなくても
いいんだよ
Mayushii is okay now,
まゆしぃは もう大丈夫だから
so you can cry for yourself, Okarin.
オカリンは オカリンのために
泣いてもいいんだよ
（岡部）
電話レンジは もういらない
We no longer need the Phone Microwave.
I met Kurisu because of it,
このマシンがあったことで
紅莉栖と出会えた
but it also hurt so many others.
けれど―
このマシンがあったことで―
たくさんの人が傷ついた
鳳凰院凶真が死んだように―
Just as Hououin Kyouma has died,
the Phone Microwave should die as well.
電話レンジもまた死ぬべきなのだ
Living should mean no do-overs.
生きることは本来
やり直しがきかないことだから
これでいいんだ
This is for the best. Right, Kurisu?
そうだよな　紅莉栖…
～
Hello?
（橋田）はい
Huh? Wh-Who's this?
えっ？ だ… 誰？
"Dad"?
父さん？
What?
何？ オカリン？
Okarin?
Okarin, there's a mysterious girl who wants to talk to you!
オカリン！
謎の女が替われってさ
（岡部）誰だ？
Who's this?
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）お願い！
今すぐ ラジ館屋上に来て
Please come to the roof of the radio building immediately!
（岡部）あ？ お前は
Who are you?
I've come from the year 2036.
（鈴羽）
私は 2036年から来た
橋田 至の娘
I'm Hashida Itaru's daughter, Amane Suzuha!
阿万音鈴羽
Suzuha?
鈴羽？
Wait!
ちょっと待て！
What are you doing here?
鈴羽が なんで
ここにいるんだ？
Please believe what I'm about to tell you.
（鈴羽）お願い
私の言うことを信じて
You must stop World War III.
第３次世界大戦を防ぐために